Mateusz Marchewka

Data Analyst

Contact

07542 812119 mmcarrot90@gmail.com Westhoughton, BL5 3FQ PORTFOLIO LINK

Key Skills

Technical:

Excel / VBA (good), SQL (good), Tableau (good), Python (intermediate), Power BI (basic), Storytelling, Statistics

Soft Skills:

Great communication, problem-solving, collaboration, critical thinking, creativity, curiosity, leadership, attention to detail, project management

Education

MASTERS DEGREE IN
JOURNALISM AND SOCIAL
AND PUBLIC
COMMUNICATION –
University of Maria CurieSklodowska – Lublin,

References

POLAND June 2014

Available upon request

About me

Successful, process-oriented manager with a strong passion for data analytics. I have been managing teams and operations in big companies such as Prolog, Five Guys, Slim Chickens and Lidl for nearly a decade. With my ability to translate business needs into data and objectives I helped my employers achieve various awards. I have also received recognition for my own performance and contributions.

Currently seeking a career change to a data analysis / data engineering role with experience in SQL, Excel and Tableau. I have finished self-learning Udemy courses on Python, SQL, VBA and Tableau. In addition, I have also finished a full-stacked bootcamp. I am a data geek who in his free time likes to improve his visualization skills.

Personal Projects

COVID ANALYSIS OVERVIEW - LINK HERE

- > Used SQL to clean, transform, manipulate and analyze real-time data source
- Used Tableau to design data-driven dashboard to provide insights into the spread of the virus and visualize pandemic trends

COFFEE SALES DASHBOARD - LINK HERE

> Interactive dashboard in Excel built using pivot tables, charts, slicers, timeline, XLOOKUP, VLOOKUP, INDEX and MATCH to visualize the data and allow users to filter it based on different criteria

CALL CENTRE DASHBOARD - LINK HERE

Used SQL to clean and analyze data to identify trends, patterns, and insights that can help improve call center performance and used Tableau to help communicate the discovered insight

Professional Experience

DEPUTY STORE MANAGER | LIDL UK | JULY 2022 - PRESENT

GENERAL MANAGER | SLIM CHICKENS | JANUARY 2022 - JULY 2022

GENERAL MANAGER | FIVE GUYS JV | MARCH 2015 - JANUARY 2022

- Analyzing and managing large amounts of data such as: sales data forecasting, inventory records, staffing levels and customer feedback to make informed business decisions
- Organizing internal workshops that helped to identify customer and business needs and provided insights that would address those needs
- > Organizing presentations to deepen the organization's knowledge of what drives effective business and which data use to support your findings
- Creating trackers, dashboards and data visualizations to get a deeper knowledge of stores progress
- Delivering weekly reports about each store's performance
- > Training, mentoring and coaching new employees to ensure they were equipped with the necessary skills to succeed in their roles